ARIA GOMES

98 Pallister Private Nepean, ON K2G 0E8 aria.gomes00@gmail.com | (613) 981-1315 ariagomes.com | linkedin.com/in/aria-gomes | github.com/AriaGomes

OBJECTIVE

Enthusiastic Computer Science graduate eager to contribute to team success through hard work, determination, and attention to detail. A clear understanding of fundamental programming concepts and trained in solving problems efficiently and creatively. Motivated to learn, grow, and improve upon established programming concepts.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Programming Languages: Java (SE & EE), Python, SQL (PostgreSQL & MySQL), C# (.NET), JavaScript, HTML & CSS, PHP, C (ANSI), C++, Assembly, Bash, Batch.

Soft Skills: Collaborating as a group and working individually with little direction, Analyzing data effectively and solving problems creatively with critical thinking. Desire to learn and research topics, ask questions on improving, and be openminded to peers' criticism. Time management skills to organize work and be a reliable member of the team.

Languages: Fluent English, intermediate level French and Portuguese.

Development Tools: Visual Studio 2019 Enterprise, Visual Studio Code, JetBrains IDE Suite, Arduino IDE, QNX Momentics IDE, NetBeans IDE, Eclipse IDE, Unity Game Engine, Git, Docker, MongoDB, WSL/Linux, Node.js, React, ESLint, Selenium, PuTTY/SSH, VMWare/VirtualBox, Yarn, Postman.

EXPERIENCE

Computer Repair Specialist *Aria's Repair*

October 2020 – Current

- Self-made, home-based business of repairing laptops and desktops.
- Tasks: Diagnosing, Troubleshooting, Customer Contact, Ordering replacement hardware, Installing new hardware, Malware removal, Data backups, Control finances, Control inventory.

Customer Service Representative Farm Boy Inc.

January 2020 – February 2021

 Tasks: Keeping inventory, Organizing deliveries, Customer service, Stocking store shelves, Creating displays with products, Closing procedures, Cleaning, Labeling dates on products.

ACHIEVEMENTS AND CERTIFICATIONS

September 2018 – December 2021: Dean's Honours List (GPA: 3.8 overall)

September 2012 – June 2018: Information & Communications Technology Specialist High Skills Major

EDUCATION

Ontario College Advanced Diploma

Algonquin College of Applied Arts and Technology

- Deans Honours List; GPA 3.8/4.0.
- Coursework Completed: C Language (ANSI C), Database (PostgreSQL),
 Interfacing (C/C++), Compilers (ANSI C), Real-Time Programming (C/C++),
 Processor Architecture (Assembly), Java Application Programming (Java SE),
 Web Enterprise Applications (Java EE), Object-Oriented Programming (Java SE),
 .NET Enterprise Application Development (C#), Game Programming (C#),
 Operating Systems Fundamentals (Linux).

September 2018 - December 2021

PROJECTS

Discover black hairstylists & barbers *Afroguide.ca*

December 2020 – December 2021

- Platform for users to easily discover hairstylists & barbers who cater to black hair.
 Users can book appointments and rate stylists. Stylists can use the platform to expose their skills to new users.
- The application uses ReactJS and Material UI for the front-end elements, NextJS and react-router-dom for routing pages, Google API with react-places-autocomplete for geolocation, autocomplete and location data.
- Tasks: Adding/Editing JavaScript code to redesign the front end, adding new features
 to enhance the user experience, Collaboration via GitHub, Meeting the client's
 requests on weekly sprints, Writing a technical report about the development of the
 project.

Linux shell inside Discord

December 2021

${\it Discord Shell}$

- Runs any Linux shell command inside of a Discord text channel.
- The Application uses node.js and discord.js to execute and connect with discord's API. child_process is used to pipe commands to the shell and pipe the output back as a discord message.
- Application was written in a few hours and was made for fun and learning how to make a docker container with my applications.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Automation, Docker, IoT, Machine Learning, and home lab/self-hosting.

References available upon request